(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T23:45:46.394326",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
始まりはきっと 一つの願い
It surely started with a single wish
それを抱いて私たちは 生まれた
Embracing it, we were born
孤独な夜空 震える指で
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingers
点と点をつなぎ合わせよう
Let's connect the dots together
Wow wow...
1次元では 寂しすぎるから
One dimension is far too lonely
私たちは 広がりを求めた
So we sought out expansion
点は線となり
Points became lines
線は立体となりCustom
Lines became 3D shapes
そこに距離が生まれたけれど
And though distance was born there...
3次元では ちょっと遠すぎるから
Three dimensions are a bit too far
私たちは 平面にも求めた
So we sought it in a 2D plane as well
点は線となり
Points became lines
線は星座となり
Lines became constellations
この夜空をつなぐよ
Connecting this night sky
自分らしく
To be myself
居られる場所を
...and find a place where I belong
気づけばずっと探していた
I realized I had been searching for it all along
きらめく星よ
Oh, glittering stars
このリズムの上
Upon this rhythm
この旗を目印に
With this flag as our guide
あの日君がいつもの
Because on that day
そこに居たから
...you were there as always
嬉しくて続けたんだ 今日まで
I was so happy that I kept going until today
忘れないでね
Please don't forget
僕らの星座は
Our constellation
君が居たから生まれた
...was born because you were here
Wow wow...
たとえ君がいつもの
Even if you are living
時を生きても
...in your usual time
何かを好きになる気持ち
Hold on to the feeling of liking something
大切に
Cherish it
歌い続けてね
...and keep on singing
僕らの星座は
Our constellation
君がいるから生まれた
...was born because you are here
夜空に輝き
Shining in the night sky
明日へとつながる
Connecting us to tomorrow
Wow wow...
未来を
We will head toward...
目指すよ
...the future.
ともに
Let's go...
行こう
...together.
これは僕らのキセキ。僕とキミと、大切なあの子の。
This is our miracle. Yours, mine, and that precious girl's.
この王国で過ごす、かけがえのない日々を綴る僕たちの物語。
Our story, chronicling the irreplaceable days spent in this kingdom.
小説「FBKINGDOM STORY」 ED1 冒頭抜粋
[Excerpt from the beginning of Novel "FBKINGDOM STORY" ED1]
僕の居る意味はどこにあるの？
Where is the meaning of my being?
誰かに必要とされたかった
I wanted to be needed by someone.
夢や希望も捨てきれないけど
Though I can't completely throw away my hopes and dreams,
なんとなく今を生きている
I'm living right now, some way or another.
あぁ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I cry out,
この声は君には届かない
This voice will not reach you.
あぁ どれだけ叫んでも
Ah, no matter how much I cry out,
この声は君には届かない
This voice will not reach you.
金木犀の匂いがした
Smelling like osmanthus,
明日のことも忘れたくなった
I began to want to forget about tomorrow.
いっそ逃げてしまおうかな
Maybe I should just run away right now?
僕は悲劇の主人公だ
I'm the protagonist of this tragedy.
やさしい人で居たいな
I wanna be a kind person,
でもそんな思いも偽善だ
But that sort of thinking is hypocritical.
誰も幸せにできないの
I can't make anyone happy,
都合良いね、涙が出るの
And when it's convenient, I'll burst into tears.
How convenient, tears stream down...
あぁ どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
あぁ どれだけ歌っても
Ah, no matter how much I sing,
この声は君には届かない
this voice will not reach you.
あぁ 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe,
この歌もいつしか終わりが来る
and this song will end before anyone knows it.
あぁ 息が苦しくなる
Ah, it's getting hard to breathe,
この地球もいつかは終わりが来る
and this earth will end someday.
金木犀の匂いをまた
Once again, the scent of osmanthus
思い出した
brought back memories.
In the dust, amid the wintry wind,
the shadow of the past... suddenly, the toll will begin.
気付けば... 駆けだしていた...
Before I knew it... I was running...
揺れ動く... 心の随に...
Following... my swaying heart...
遠ざかる... 白い壁...
The white walls... fade into the distance...
一度も... 振り返らずに...
Without... ever looking back...
《生命》が... 消え逝く季節の...
As life... fades away in this season...
胸を刺す... 気配の中で...
Amid the... heart-piercing chill...
迫り来る... 暗い闇...
The dark darkness... drawing near...
二度と... 明けないような気がして...
Feeling as though... the dawn would never come again...
転がり落ちそうな心
My heart, on the verge of tumbling down,
必死に抱きとめていた...
I desperately held on to it...
星空へと続く長い坂道は
The long slope leading to the starry sky...
永遠にも... 思えたから...
seemed to go on forever...
咲く花や... 散りぬるを...
Flowering blossoms... will eventually scatter...
神代の《時代》より繰り返す...
Repeating since the age of the gods...
私はそれを... 美しいとは...
But I have never...
思ったことがない...
thought of it as beautiful...
絶えず久方の... 春の陽を...
The eternal... spring sunlight...
仮初めの影が奪い合う...
Transient shadows contest with each other...
その営みを... 美しいとは...
But I have never...
思ったことがない...
thought of those ways as beautiful...
諦めながら... 生きてた...
I lived... while giving up...
何も望まないように... それでも...
Wishing for nothing... and yet...
手放せなかった... 最後の願いを...
I couldn't let go of... my final wish...
握り締めて... 駆け上がる...
Clutching it tightly... I run up...
尾丸ポルカ
[Omaru Polka]
猫又おかゆ
[Nekomata Okayu]
大神ミオ
[Ookami Mio]
天音かなた
[Amane Kanata]
さくらみこ
[Sakura Miko]
鷹嶺ルイ
[Takane Lui]
フワワ・アビスガード / モココ・アビスガード
[Fuwawa Abyssgard / Mococo Abyssgard]
白上フブキ
[Shirakami Fubuki]
冥界 Halloween Night!
[Title: Underworld Halloween Night!]
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, who live so recklessly, are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが得をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily benefit
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I am the only one who will not laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも 我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I will not laugh!
あぁ 人は滅んでゆく 綻んでゆく
Ah, humans will perish, unraveling...
才を妬み合い 富を奪い合い
Envying each other's talents, fighting over wealth
あぁ 人は滅んでゆく 綻んでゆく
Ah, humans will perish, unraveling...
その果てに見えた海は 地獄だろうか？ それとも地獄だろうか？
Is the ocean seen at the end of it hell? Or is it hell?
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて
You, who live so recklessly, are laughed at
楽に生きる奴らが得をする世界で
In a world where those who live easily benefit
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You who live honestly are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳とする世界で
in a world where those who live by lies benefit.
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will never let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will never forget!
身を粉にして働いても
Even if you work yourself to the bone,
感謝されないことも……（シバシバ）
and are never appreciated...
「自己犠牲」を受け入れても
Even if you accept "self-sacrifice,"
限界がもうやってくるから
you will eventually reach your limit,
自分を大事に愛せばいい
so you should just love and cherish yourself.
それは他人を愛すること
That is what it means to love others.
ああ人は滅んでゆく
Ah, humans perish...
滅んでゆく
...they perish.
元に戻ってゆく
They return to how they were.
ああ人は泳いでゆく
Ah, humans swim...
救われてゆく
...they are saved.
君に逢えたから……
Because I was able to meet you...
君を愛したから……
Because I loved you...
君が闘うなら……
If you are going to fight...
僕も闘うから……
I will fight too...
我武者羅に生きるお前が笑われて...
You who live recklessly are laughed at,
楽に生きる奴らが徳をする世界で
in a world where those who live easily benefit.
我だけはお前のことを笑わない！
I alone will never laugh at you!
皆が指差し笑おうとも我は笑わない！
Even if everyone points and laughs, I won't laugh!
正直に生きるお前が貶されて
You who live honestly are disparaged,
嘘で生きる奴らが徳とする世界で
in a world where those who live by lies benefit.
我だけはお前の腕を離さない！
I alone will never let go of your arm!
時を刻み忘れようとも我は離さない！
Even if time forgets to tick, I won't let go!
我は忘れない！
I will never forget!
それじゃあ今夜は、この王国のお話をしていこう。
Well then, tonight, let's talk about this kingdom.
嘘か真か、ここに記されている本は内容がコロコロと変わってしまう、不思議な本でね。
True or false, the contents of the book recorded here keep changing constantly. It's a mysterious book.
さて、今回はどんなお話になっているかな。
Now, I wonder what kind of story it will be this time.
これはあるサーカスの一団が王国へ訪れ、
This is a story about a certain circus troupe visiting the kingdom,
まだ未熟な座長さんが綺麗びやかなステージに包まれたお話。
and a story of a still-inexperienced ringmaster enveloped in a gorgeous stage.
あぁ……これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング！
Ah... this is the dream ending I wished for!
さあ、今日も始まりました～！
Now then, it's starting today as well!
煌びやか、享楽のパレード
A brilliant, pleasure-filled parade.
常識もここじゃ無関係
Common sense doesn't matter here.
踊れ歌え騒げ全て忘れて
Dance, sing, and make noise, forgetting everything!
細かいことは置いといて
Set aside the small details,
とりあえず身を任せてみな
and just surrender yourself for now.
幸福を少し分けるような饗宴
A feast to share a bit of happiness...
Show Time!
積もりゆく不安や後悔
The piling anxiety and regrets,
今だけはちょっと目を背けて
just look away from them for a moment.
そのままじゃ楽しめないじゃん
You can't enjoy it like that, can you?
この場だけは何もかもを忘れて！
Just forget everything in this place!
幾千の価値観全部
All the thousands of values,
引っ括め楽しませたげる！
I'll lump them together and entertain you!
百鬼夜行もビックリの
Even surprising the Night Parade of One Hundred Demons,
隊を成している
they form a troupe.
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け
A comedy mimicking the bizarre begins its act.
一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
With just one look, you'll instantly be captivated!?
どんな愛も受け入れでくれる
It accepts any kind of love.
ここだけはあなたの理想郷
Only here is your utopia.
「もう間もなく主役の登場、
"The main star will appear shortly.
一時でも目を離さないで！」
Don't look away even for a second!"
眩しいほどのステージが始まる。
A dazzling stage is about to begin.
華々しい
A spectacular...
華々しいスポットライトの中
Amid the brilliant spotlight,
目を奪うような妙技の数々
numerous eye-catching, wonderful feats.
この空間が世界で一番
This space is the number one in the world,
“娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
worthy of the name "entertainment!"
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で
With thunderous cheers and applause,
ショーが終わっていく
the show is coming to an end.
まあ、これはあくまで理想の話なんですが
Well, this is only an ideal story, though.
さて、今日も始めましょうか...
Well, shall we begin today as well...
あ～；；またやっちゃった
Ah... I messed up again!
実際はご覧の通り、まだまだ未熟な見習いなんです；；
Actually, as you can see, I'm still a very inexperienced apprentice.
先人に憧れ持って 私
Longing to be like my predecessors, I...
私も！と飛び込んだものの
...jumped right in, saying, "Me too!"
現実はそんな簡単に
But reality doesn't go...
上手くいかないな
...so easily.
もう一回！
One more time!
怪奇模した喜劇が幕開け 一目見ればたちまち虜に！？
The curtain rises on a comedy mimicking the bizarre! Just one look and you'll be instantly captivated!?
え？既にそれさっき見た？なら、
Huh? You've already seen that just now? Then,
飽き性なあなたにも【朗報】
here's some good news for you easily-bored folks!
Q.ちょっと前の模倣をするだけ？
Q: Just imitating what we did a moment ago?
A.繰り返しじゃつまらない！
A: Just repeating it is boring!
だから、ここから先は趣向を変えてみよう！
So, from here on out, let's change things up!
ドタバタなサーカスの行方は 誰にも自分すらも分からない！？
No one, not even we ourselves, knows where this chaotic circus is headed!?
私を選んだ君だけでも楽しんでってよ～～～！！！
Just you, who chose me, make sure you have fun!!!
損させないから
Because we won't let you down!
いつの日か皆と楽しめるショーがしたいんだよな
Someday, I want to perform a show that everyone can enjoy!
だからこそ、こんなとこで挫けるわけとかな～い！
That's exactly why we can't give up in a place like this!
言葉なんかじゃ言い表せない あの感動を私もいつか...
That emotion that words can't describe... I too, someday...
とても偉大なこのステージに見合っているか分かんないけれど
I don't know if I'm suited for this incredibly grand stage, but...
観客全て、私の色で染め尽くしてやろう！
I'll paint every single member of the audience in my own color!
手始めに、今、眼の前の君たちからいくよ～～～！！！
To start off, we're coming for you guys right in front of us!!!
創造しよう！
Let's create it!
華々しいスポットライトの中 目を奪うような妙技の数々
Amidst the spectacular spotlights, numerous breathtaking and brilliant feats!
この空間が世界で一番 “娯楽”の名に相応しいんだ！
This space is the most deserving of the name "Entertainment" in the whole world!
割れんばかりの歓声と拍手で ショーが終わっていく
With deafening cheers and applause, the show comes to a close.
あぁ... これが私が望んだ夢のエンディング
Ah... this is the dream ending that I've wished for.
これは、花の国のお姫様が、この王国へいらっしゃった時のお話。
This is the story of when the princess of the Flower Kingdom came to this kingdom.
まだみんな彼女の事を知らない頃だったので、国民の大半は、「アホの子」なんて言ってたけど、
Since no one knew her well back then, most of the citizens called her a "silly kid," but...
とっても心優しく、そして気さくで、頼りになるお姫様だったんだよ。
...she was a very kind-hearted, friendly, and dependable princess.
なんたって、みこはお姫様なんだから！
After all, Miko is a princess!
女神！ 聖女！ 叡智！ 聡明！ 慈愛！ 博愛！
Goddess! Saint! Wisdom! Sagacity! Mercy! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Indeed!
あたし なんたって お姫様
After all, I am a princess!
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine in this life of mine.
ですわー！
Indeed!
一生安泰でイージーモード！って思ったら勝手にどうぞ？
Think it's a lifetime of safety on easy mode? Think whatever you want!
世間はいつも 風向き次第
The world is always at the mercy of the wind.
有象無象ばかりでホント
Seriously, it's just a bunch of nobodies,
人間不信になっちゃう！
...it makes me lose faith in humanity!
気づいたの この世界に
I realized that in this world,
血も涙もないこと
there is neither blood nor tears.
あれもダメ、これもダメ、それもダメ、どれもダメ
That's no good, this is no good, that's no good, none of it's any good.
現実は世知辛い
Reality is tough.
改変だ...
We need to rewrite it...
全部改変ですわー！
Let's rewrite everything!
あたし なんたって お姫様
After all, I am a princess!
この人生におけるヒロイン
The heroine in this life of mine.
悲しいシナリオも
Even a sad scenario,
全部全部書き換えちゃうの
I will rewrite absolutely all of it.
だってだって お姫様
Because, after all, I'm a princess!
自分の物語くらいは
At least for my own story,
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
I have to enjoy it with plenty of sparkle!
今に見てなさい！
Just you watch!
運命なんて
Something like fate,
改変して差し上げますわ！
I shall rewrite it for you!
だれ？だれ？ だれ？だれ？だれ？
Who? Who? Who? Who? Who?
裏で糸を引いてるのはだれ？
Who is the one pulling the strings behind the scenes?
操り人形だなんて
Saying I'm just a puppet...
ごめんだわ まったく
No thanks, absolutely not.
上品な顔をしてても
Even if they wear a polite face,
黒幕はあの人かも
the mastermind might be that person.
まずはあたしが
First, I...
強くならなきゃ
...must become strong,
未来は変わらない
or the future won't change.
改革だ...
It's a revolution...
自分改革ですわー！
A personal revolution!
そうよ なんたって お姫様
That's right! After all, I'm a princess!
あたしこそ最高権力者
I am the one with the supreme authority!
生涯のすべての主導権は
The initiative for everything in my life...
こちらにあるわ
...is right here with me.
だってだって お姫様
Because, after all, I'm a princess!
自分で決めたことくらいは
At least the things I've decided myself...
わがままに行かなきゃ
I've got to be selfish!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Indeed! Indeed! Indeed!
女神！ 聖女！
Goddess! Saint!
叡智！ 聡明！
Wisdom! Intelligence!
慈愛！ 博愛！
Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Indeed!
今日も軽くステップする
Lightly stepping again today,
運命の歯車が踊りだす
the gears of fate begin to dance.
顔を上げたその時
The moment I look up,
ほら世界が恋をする
look, the world falls in love.
あたしハッピーエンドプリンセス この人生におけるヒロイン
I'm the Happy End Princess, the heroine of this life!
すったもんだある日々も全部全部愛してみせるの
Even the chaotic days, I'll love them all!
ハッピーエンドプリンセス 自分の物語くらいは
Happy End Princess! At least in my own story,
キラキラ楽しまなきゃ
I must enjoy it sparklingly!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Indeed! Indeed! Indeed!
全力で生き抜かなきゃ
I've got to live life to the fullest!
ですわ！ですわ！ですわ！
Indeed! Indeed! Indeed!
今に見てなさい！
Just you wait and see!
運命なんて
Even fate itself...
改変して差し上げますわ！
...I shall rewrite it for you!
女神！ 聖女！
Goddess! Saint!
叡智！ 聡明！
Wisdom! Intelligence!
慈愛！ 博愛！
Affection! Philanthropy!
ですわ！
Indeed!
王国で一躍有名になった小説の1つじゃないか
Isn't that one of those novels that suddenly became famous in the kingdom?
…ある女学生探偵と推理作家の先生が織りなす楽しい…え？
...A delightful story woven by a female student detective and a mystery writer... eh?
いやいやこの事件が実際にあったのかまではわからないよ、
No, no, we don't know if this incident actually happened,
demo, kono shiriizu wa sugoku ninki nandesu yo ne.
but this series is super popular, isn't it?
わかりました！犯人はあなたですね！
I've got it! The culprit is you!
あっ、あっ、あっ、あー、ベーカー街(ストリート)ラインなら七つ道具はしまっちゃえ
Ah, ah, ah, ah, if we're on the Baker Street line, pack up your seven tools!
あ、黒い外套(マント)羽織った名探偵がまた一人姿を消したという
Ah, they say another great detective in a black cloak has vanished.
綾なす辻のアリス側　横溝・そうじ・江戸川か
Alice on the colorful crossroads, is it Yokomizo, Souji, or Edogawa?
神田最弱探偵さん　こんなのどう居ると思う？
Kanda's weakest detective, do you think someone like this exists?
ナンマンダブ・ステップ踏み　脳髄、これ密室なりや
Dancing the Nanmandabu step, is the brain a locked room?
愚と智で出会った人　愚と智で別れましょう
Met in folly and wisdom / Let's part in folly and wisdom.
謎解きはこれから
The mystery solving begins now!
犯人はあなたですね！
The culprit is you!
列車トリック 発火トリック 難事件　推理作家の先生さん
Train tricks, ignition tricks, difficult cases / Mr. Mystery Writer.
あはは、うだらうだらうだらうだら今何ページ目？
Ahaha, idle chatter, idle chatter, what page are we on now?
あぁもう頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
Ah, my head is already getting all tangled up, but...
どとはらいどとこむ　あちゃちゃちゃぱりぱり
Dotoharai dotcom / Achachacha paripari...
エブリバディわこそば　謎はおやつに入りません
Everybody wakosoba / The mystery is not included in snacks!
どとはらいどとこむ　あちゃちゃちゃどしゃりどしゃり
Dotoharai dotcom / Achachacha dosharidoshari...
エブリバディあいまいまいまい
Everybody aimaimaimai...
エトセトラいへんぱはからずなき万端さん続いてご静聴
Et cetera, unusual things happening suddenly, please continue listening.
織り円と急行車の窓　あの怪盗達が暗躍するという
By the window of the Orient Express, they say those phantom thieves operate in secret.
高来 北二三 海野原 坂口暗号無視したら
Takarai, Kitanisann, Uminohara, if we ignore Sakaguchi's code...
ＡＢＣだか恵比寿だか　レモンドちゃんとして
ABC or Ebisu, act properly, Lemon-de.
甲が乙を隠す　そんじゃ降参？　有栖さんお疲れさん
A hides B, then surrender? Good job, Alice-san.
四捨五入やってみな　四捨五入どこ行った？
Try rounding it off, where did the rounding go?
謎解きはまだまだ
The mystery solving is far from over!
そして誰がいなくなった？
And then, who disappeared?
およしになっておやめになって怪事件　お下げ揺らす探偵さん
Please stop, please cut it out, mysterious cases, detective swaying her braids.
ノックスベイビー　ヴァン・ダインベイビー　行かないで　あぁもう先生の意地悪は毎度のこと
Knox baby, Van Dine baby, don't go / Ah, the writer's meanness is a regular thing.
どとはらいどとこむ　あちゃちゃちゃぱりぱり　エブリバディわこそば　たまには自分で考えたまえ
Dotoharai dotcom / Achachacha paripari / Everybody wakosoba / Think for yourself once in a while!
どとはらいどとこむ　あちゃちゃちゃどしゃりどしゃり
Dotoharai dotcom / Achachacha dosharidoshari...
エブリバディ アリバイ ないないない
Everybody! Alibi! There's none, none, none!
怪盗レミの罠にハマり、次々と姿を消していく名探偵たち。
Trapped by Phantom Thief Remi, the great detectives disappear one after another.
そして探偵の居ぬ間に、人々の心は密室となった。
And while the detectives were away, people's hearts became locked rooms.
「でも、それならどうしてお私だけが無事だったんでしょうか？」
But, if so, why was I the only one who was safe?
「その答えはひとつしか考えられない」
"There is only one conceivable answer to that."
「と、いうと……？」
"Which is...?"
「あまりにも無能すぎるがゆえに、
"Because you are so utterly incompetent..."
君は探偵として勘定にも入れられていなかったのだ！」
"...you weren't even counted as a detective!"
「ひどーい！」
"How cruel!"
およしになって おやめになって 怪事件
Please stop, please don't do it, mysterious cases!
お騒ぎ揺らす 探偵さん
Stirring up a commotion, Mr. Detective!
ノックすれば ガチの目論見
If you knock, there lies a serious plot!
行かないで
Please don't go!
おおもう 先生のいじわる いけず
Oh dear, you're so mean and unkind, Sensei!
列車トリック 発火トリック 難事件
Train tricks, ignition tricks, difficult cases!
推理作家の先生！
Mystery writer Sensei!
うだらはだらうだらはだら言わないで ああもう
Don't say such nonsense, oh geez!
頭がこんがらがってきたけれど
My head is getting all tangled up, but...
かわいやかわいや トリック暴いて
How cute, how cute, expose the trick...
通りゃんせ
...and pass through!
小さい2人の子供が約束した、
Two small children made a promise...
ずっといっしょに笑っていようの約束。
...a promise to always laugh together.
今もなお、2人の絆は確かなもので…
Even now, their bond remains certain...
…友情と愛情が織りなす素敵な物語。
...a wonderful story woven of friendship and love.
あははっ…なんでもないことに、妙にツボっちゃう時あるよねっ
Ahaha... sometimes we burst out laughing at the most trivial things, right?
あー恋に落ちたまゆら 開花止まらないや
Ah, falling in love for a fleeting moment, the blooming won't stop
何度も捲って 心をかし
Turning the pages over and over, my heart is charmed
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだ今や
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now
腹よじるくらい笑う
Laughing so hard my stomach twists
ずっと一緒に笑う
Always laughing together
きみが持ってる白い花に
To the white flower that you hold,
あたし見合わないな 悲しくなる
I don't seem to suit it, and it makes me sad
無垢な恋とか正しさとか
About pure love or what is right,
誰も教えてくれなかった
no one ever taught me
昨日会ったばっかで
We only just met yesterday,
今日もどっか会えたらなんて思う暮らし 慎ましくないよね
yet wishing we'd meet again today isn't very modest, is it?
全部許されたの びっくりしちゃってさ
Everything was forgiven, it completely surprised me
涙あふれてたよ
and my tears overflowed
もう愛になる花歌 透き通った空に
A humming song that has turned into love under the transparent sky
手を繋いでった 夢のしるし
We held hands, a sign of our dream
どんな前世だってさ 忘れたっていいんだ
No matter what our past lives were, it's fine to forget them
きみと笑えるなら
as long as I can laugh with you
心が触れるたび綺麗な音鳴る
Every time our hearts touch, a beautiful sound rings out
目と目が合ってくすぐったいね
Our eyes meet, and it's ticklish
なんでもないこと妙にツボるね
We burst out laughing at the most trivial things
全部教えてくれてありがとう
Thank you for teaching me everything
きみが持ってる白い花を
The white flower that you hold,
あたしの紅色と合わせたら
if I combine it with my crimson red...
霜が溶けては雲が行く
The frost melts and the clouds drift away
もう寒くないよ
I'm not cold anymore
あー恋に落ちたまゆら 開花止まらないや
Ah, falling in love for a fleeting moment, the blooming won't stop
何度も捲って 心をかし
Turning the pages over and over, my heart is charmed
泣いてばっかだったの それがどうだ今や
I used to do nothing but cry, but look at me now
腹よじるくらい笑う
Laughing so hard my stomach twists
ずっと一緒に笑って
Laughing together forever...
(恋に落ちたまゆら)
(falling in love for a fleeting moment)
心をかし
my heart is charmed
(愛になる花歌)
(a humming song turning into love)
ずっと一緒に笑う
always laughing together
最後の日を笑う
laughing on our final day
これは、遠い遠い名も知らぬ世界で、
This is a story in a far, far away, nameless world...
死の呪いがかけられた 少女のお話
This is the story of a girl cursed with death.
遠い遠い時の果て そこに住まう人は皆
At the end of a time far, far away, everyone who lived there...
皆永遠の命をもつ 世界での話
...possessed eternal life in that world's tale.
赤い実の成る木の下 生まれながらに
Under the tree bearing red fruit, from the moment she was born...
死の呪いがかけられた 少女の話
...this is the story of a girl cursed with death.
色付いた街外れ 蒼く光る湖畔
On the colorful outskirts of town, by the blue glowing lakeshore...
赤い実のお菓子屋
...stands a sweet shop of red fruit.
ちょっぴり寒くなった今日は 妙に誇らしげ
Today, as it grew a bit colder, she felt strangely proud...
自信作を売りに行く
...and went to sell her masterpiece.
待ってて 今度こそ 美味しいんだから
Just wait, it's definitely delicious this time!
時計塔の見える市 驚いた 珍しく賑やかね
At the market by the clock tower, she was surprised to see it so lively.
La La Lu La Lucky!!
物憂げな街の隅 ひとり
Alone in a gloomy corner of the town...
赤い実のパイ どうですか 自信作なの
"Would you like a red fruit pie? It's my masterpiece."
さんぽのびともひとつも売れやせず
Not a single passerby bought one.
少女を見て蔑む人達
People looked at the girl with disdain.
みんなと何も変わらないのに
Even though she is no different from anyone else.
美味しくできたのに
Even though she made it so delicious.
今日も声は届かないのね
Today, too, her voice won't reach anyone.
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if she has become invisible.
そうして誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And so, everyone pretended not to notice.
何故なら少女は呪われているから
Because the girl is cursed.
死んた世界で唯ひとり生きていた少女の話
This is the story of a girl who lived all alone in a dead world.
夜なべでアレンジパイとにっこりスマイル引っ提げ
Working through the night, with an improved pie and a bright smile...
少女はまだ諦めない
...the girl still hasn't given up.
時計塔の針も空を指してお腹も鳴るそんな時
As the clock tower's hand pointed to the sky and her stomach rumbled...
ふと後ろから人が少女を押す
...suddenly, someone pushed her from behind.
甘いカゴは落ちる
The sweet basket fell.
お菓子を踏み行く人達 平気な顔をしてさ
People trampled the treats, completely unbothered.
惨めに拾い集める
As she miserably gathered them up...
ふともうひとりの手が
...suddenly, another hand appeared.
どろどろのパイを徐に口に入れて「美味しいね」
He slowly put the muddy pie into his mouth and said, "It's delicious."
その声で色は溢れた
With those words, color overflowed.
まるで輪郭を描いたみたいだわ
It's as if outlines were finally drawn.
そうして彼は手を差し出した
And so, he reached out his hand to her.
何故なら少女に呪われて...
Because even if he is cursed by the girl...
死んだ世界で唯ふたり生きていた遠い物語
This is the distant tale of two people who lived alone in a dead world.
街の人達は哀れむ 赤い実を食べて呪われた者を
The townsfolk pitied those cursed by eating the red fruit.
永遠に生きられずに死ぬのか
"Will they die without being able to live forever?"
嗚呼 なんて可哀想な話
"Ah, what a tragic story..."
ふたりは笑う それでも笑う
The two of them laughed, and still, they laughed.
La La La とっても素敵な呪いね
La La La, what a truly wonderful curse.
例え明日死んでも 『今』が確かで大切になるから
Even if we die tomorrow, "now" becomes real and precious to us.
もう声は届かないのね
Her voice won't reach anyone anymore.
まるで透明になったみたいだわ
It's as if she has become invisible.
そうして誰もが知らぬ振りをした
And so, everyone pretended not to notice.
何故なら世界が呪われているから
Because the world itself is cursed.
『永遠』の呪いは解かれていた
The curse of "eternity" had been broken.
まるでふたりの方が狂ったみたいだろう
It's almost as if the two of them were the ones who went mad.
そしていつか笑うように眠る
And then, sleep someday as if smiling...
何故ならふたりは放たれているから
Because the two of us have been set free.
死んだ世界でただふたりだけが幸せだった
In this dead world, only we two were happy.
さて、今日はこれくらいにしておきましょう。
Well, let's call it a day here.
…そろそろ時間になりましたし
...Since it's about that time anyway.
…え？ どこへ向かうのかって？
...Eh? Where are we going, you ask?
今日は何の日かご存知ないのですか？
Don't you know what day it is today?
今日は、この王国の地下深くにある冥界でのハロウィンパーティーですよ！
Today is the Halloween party in the underworld, deep beneath this kingdom!
死者と生者が楽しむ年に一度のお祭りです。
It's a once-a-year festival for the dead and the living to enjoy together.
さぁ、一緒に向かいましょう。
Come, let's head there together.
でも、気を付けて。
But please, be careful.
パーティーとは言え、死者が住まう冥界です。
Even if it's a party, it is the underworld where the dead reside.
誰かの思念や死者達によって奇妙な事が起こるかもしれません。
Strange things might happen due to someone's lingering thoughts or the dead.
でも、決してそちらに耳を傾けすぎてはいけませんよ…
But you must never pay too much attention to them...
それでは、参りましょう。
Well then, let us go.
蒼炎
[Title: Blue Flame]
誰かが言いました
Someone once said...
激しく燃えるものほど
...that the more intensely something burns...
煌めく引き換えに
...in exchange for its brilliant sparkle...
その身をすぐ焦がしきると
...the sooner it completely consumes itself.
数ある燭台に
Upon the countless candlesticks...
お好きな火を灯しましょう
...let's light your flame of choice.
期待と裏腹に
Contrary to expectations...
燻ればお生憎様
...if it only smolders, how unfortunate.
ランランランラン 右手には錆びた時計
Lan, lan, lan, lan, a rusted watch in my right hand...
ランランランラン 左には油の筒
...lan, lan, lan, lan, a tube of oil in my left.
蝋のドレスを着飾って さあ固定
Now, dress up in a gown of wax.
激しく 儚く
Violently, fleetingly...
蒼く燃ゆる花びら
...petals burning in a blue flame.
瞬き ゆらめく
Flickering and wavering...
生を彩り照らせ
...color and light up this life...
いずれ尽き果てる未来へと
...toward a future destined to eventually exhaust itself.
揺り籠の目の前で
Right in front of the cradle...
遍く飛び交う銃弾
...bullets fly far and wide.
指だけ動かせば
With just a flick of a finger...
容易くその火は潰える
...that flame is easily extinguished.
仮初の情熱で 焼け爛れた舌では
With a tongue blistered by transient passion...
上手く喋ることが できないようで
...it seems I cannot speak very well.
喉元過ぎても 毒を孕ませて
Harbouring poison even if the danger passes...
やがては
...eventually...
やがては肺を腐らせるでしょう
Eventually, it will rot your lungs.
揺らぐ死と生の狭間
Swaying in the threshold between life and death,
焼ける心と歌う
I sing with a burning heart.
描いた最愛の終幕を
The beloved finale I envisioned.
激しく 儚く 蒼く燃ゆる花びら
Violently, fleetingly, the blue burning petals...
瞬き ゆらめく 生を彩り照らせ
Flickering and swaying, coloring and illuminating life,
いずれ尽き果てるその先へ
Towards the future that will eventually exhaust itself.
あちらの世界に引きずり込まれないうちに 早く会場へ向かわないといけませんね。
Before we get dragged into that world, we must head to the venue quickly.
気を付けてついてきてくださいね、
Please be careful and follow me.
あまり深入りすると、おっと…
If you delve too deep, oops...
そうそう、知らないほうがきっと懸命ですよ。
That's right, it's definitely wiser not to know.
なんだかすっごく心地が良いよね。
Somehow, it feels incredibly comfortable, doesn't it?
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
[Title: Amazing Happy Halloween Night]
気づけば見知らぬ世界に立っていた
Before I knew it, I was standing in an unfamiliar world.
何処かも分からず毎日毎日毎日泣いていた
Not knowing where I was, day after day after day, I was crying.
なんて暇も無く
I didn't even have time to do that!
Happy Time! おかしな面々が
Happy Time! Odd characters...
Happy Time! おどけて転がるの
Happy Time! Fool around and tumble.
Happy Time! その馬鹿馬鹿しさに
Happy Time! With all that silliness,
希望も恐怖もなくなった
both hope and fear disappeared.
確かそうアタシには
I'm pretty sure I had...
為すべき仕事 愛の棲家
...a job to do, and a loving home.
パンプキン ヘッドギア
Pumpkins, headgear...
だけどなんかどーでもいい
But somehow, none of it matters.
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
Now it has begun, the night of dreams!
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music echoes and won't stop playing.
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Shout in unison, for today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lanterns, tricks, let's let loose!
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth the effort.
なんでもありさ何故って今日は
Anything goes, because today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
It's gone! It's gone!
出口はないんだってそう永遠に
There's no exit, yes, forever.
消えちゃった！消えちゃった！
It's gone! It's gone!
思想 ルール 倫理 関係ない
Beliefs, rules, ethics—they don't matter!
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
「私はロボットではありません」に
On the "I am not a robot" prompt,
無心でチェックし回答するけれど
I mindlessly check the box and answer,
本当にそうかな
but is that really true?
Happy Life! とりま音に乗せて
Happy Life! For now, ride the beat.
Happy Life! デタラメに踊るの
Happy Life! Dance randomly.
Happy Life! その繰り返しのなか
Happy Life! In that endless cycle,
懐疑心も失った
I even lost my skepticism.
意志のない様まるで
Lacking any will, just like...
ロボトミーした電気羊
...a lobotomized electric sheep.
ナイトメア NPC
A nightmare, an NPC...
だけどなんか心地がいい
But somehow, it feels quite nice.
What?
おっと音声が乱れました
Oops, the audio got distorted.
お気になさらずに皆々様
Don't let it bother you, everyone.
そんなお口は縫い合わせて
Let's sew up those mouths of yours.
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
良い子の口にはチョコとキャンディ
In the mouths of good kids go chocolate and candy.
歯に衣着せてっちゃ噛み合わない
Mincing words won't get us anywhere.
気を取り直しみんなでどうぞ
Pull yourselves together and join in, everyone!
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
知っちゃった！知っちゃった！
I found out! I found out!
全部全部理解した
I understood everything.
だから何も見たくねぇわ
That's why I don't want to see a single thing!
さぁ始まった夢の夜だ
Now it has begun, the night of dreams!
音楽が響いて鳴り止まない
The music echoes and won't stop playing.
声を揃えて叫べ今日は
Shout in unison, for today is...
アメイジングハッピーハロウィンナイト
Amazing Happy Halloween Night!
ジャック いたずら 無礼講だ
Jack-o'-lanterns, tricks, let's let loose!
真面目に生きても割に合わない
Living seriously isn't worth the effort.
トリック・オア・トリート！
Trick or treat!
お菓子をくれても
Even if you give me sweets,
イタズラはしちゃうよ！
I'll still play a trick on you!
ようこそ everyone 身の毛もよだつこの spooky night
Welcome, everyone, to this hair-raising spooky night!
腹の底まで痺れ
Numb down to the bottom of your stomach...
kick & bass & hats & trumpet
ランタンと swingin' beat 赤い紐で踊り狂えば
With the lantern and a swingin' beat, if we dance madly with red ribbons,
浮世の憂いも忘れられるでしょ
you'll surely forget the worries of this fleeting world, right?
近頃巷じゃ お化けよりも怖い人たち
Lately around town, there are people scarier than ghosts,
増えすぎちゃってすぐに 1out, 2out, 3out, KO!!
who've multiplied too much and immediately: 1 out, 2 out, 3 out, KO!!
コンプライアンスも 厳しい世の中ですが
Although compliance is strict in this world nowadays,
恐怖のリライト 請け負います
we'll take charge of rewriting your fears.
GIVE ME A CHERRY PIE
それとも may I choke you up?
or may I choke you up?
GIVE ME A FLOWY DRESS
それとも may I stab you to death?
or may I stab you to death?
poison, rope, cake and tea
knife, scissors, R.I.P.
choose one... choose one... choose one...
「さぁ選んで」
"Now, choose."
なんちゃって
Just kidding!
ドッキリ大成功 響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
The prank was a big success! With the resounding fanfare...
にっこり笑っちゃってはいピース
smile brightly and say cheese!
あー怖かったななんて
Saying "Ah, that was so scary,"
座り込んで涙目で
sitting down with teary eyes,
笑う顔見たいな
I want to see your laughing face!
ちっちゃな箱の中の モンスターに怯えるくらいなら
If you're going to be frightened by a monster inside a tiny box,
いつだってここにおいで
you can always come here!
もっとずっと本能的で楽しくなれる
You can become much more instinctively happy!
恐怖と踊っちゃおうぜ
Let's dance with fear!
騒々相転移でキマってカタルシス
A chaotic phase transition triggers catharsis!
もういっちょ 感情ジェットコースターで ゴキゲンデトックス
One more time, a mood detox on an emotional roller coaster!
満月が暴く醜悪な本性
The full moon reveals our ugly true nature,
デタラメに杖振り回し hocus pocus
waving our wands randomly, hocus pocus!
劣等感を苗床に育つ呪いを
The curse grown in the seedbed of inferiority complexes,
摘み取る術を知ってるかい？
do you know the way to pluck it out?
「迷える哀れな子羊たちよ」
"O pitiful, lost lambs,"
「お菓子が欲しいかい？」
"do you want sweets?"
「それとも安らぎが欲しいかい？」
"Or do you want peace?"
「永遠に求め続けるの？」
"Will you keep seeking forever?"
「それならば、ずっと苦しいままだ」
"Then, you will remain suffering forever."
「恐怖からの解放によって」
"If there is salvation that can be achieved"
「成し得る救済があるのならば」
"through liberation from fear,"
「この目隠しはそのままで」
"then leave this blindfold on."
「さぁ、」
"Now,"
「イタズラ完了」
"trick complete."
永遠に断ち切れない 呪いの鎖に囚われ
Trapped in a chain of curses that can never be broken,
朽ち果ててしまう前に
before you completely rot away...
脳みそちょっと弄るだけであら不思議！
Just a little tinkering with your brain, and oh, wonder!
こんなに気持ち良くて
It feels so good...
気分爽快
and refreshing!
なんちゃって
Just kidding!
ドッキリ大成功 響くパンパカパンファンファーレで
The prank was a big success! With the resounding fanfare...
にっこり笑っちゃってはいポーズ
smile brightly and pose!
あー幸せだったななんて
Saying "Ah, I was so happy,"
へたり込んで涙目で
slumping down with teary eyes,
笑う顔っていいな
a laughing face is so wonderful!
もう苦しまなくていいよ こんなに頑張ったんだから
You don't have to suffer anymore, since you've worked so hard!
躊躇わずこっちにおいで
Come over here without hesitation!
もうずっと本能的に気持ちいいだけの
To a goal that is just instinctively pleasurable,
ゴールを見せてあげる
I'll show you the goal!
困難極まってこそ光るカタルシス
Catharsis shines brightest when difficulties reach their peak!
もういっちょ 因果全リセットで タマシイデトックス
One more time, a soul detox with a complete reset of causality!
いつかの、あったかもしれない世界の出来事までをも、
Even the events of some world that might have existed once...
この冥界ではこうして思念として漂っているんだね。
...are floating here in this Underworld as thoughts.
あまり深入りしてはいけないよ。
You shouldn't delve too deep into them.
こういうのが一番たちが悪い。
Things like this are the most troublesome.
私はただ、あなたを愛していただけ。
I was only... loving you.
物言わぬ唇に生気を吹き込んで
Breathing life into those silent lips,
今宵「あなた」は蘇る
tonight, "you" shall return to life...
あの頃の姿で。
...in your form from back then.
白肌の娘が咳をした。
The pale-skinned girl coughed.
「この身貴方に捧げるわ」
"I offer this body to you."
白服の医者が囁いた。
The doctor in white whispered,
「迎えに行くよ」
"I'll come for you."
白肌の娘は朽ち果てた。
The pale-skinned girl decayed,
世界の誰にも見捨てられ、
abandoned by everyone in the world.
白服の医者は哀れんで、
The doctor in white took pity on her,
誰も知らない居場所で眠らせた。
and laid her to rest in a place no one knew.
朽ちてもまだ
Though decayed, she was still
美しい顔で、
so beautiful.
ふたりしかいない霊廟で、
In the mausoleum with only the two of them,
医者は恋をした。
the doctor fell in love.
それは永遠の恋か。
Was it eternal love...
禁断の行為か。
...or a forbidden act?
また逢いたいと願うだけ。
I only wished to see her again.
それが罪なのでしょうか。
Could that truly be a sin?
物言わぬ唇に
Into those silent lips...
生気を吹き込んで、
...breathing the breath of life,
今宵ふたりは結ばれる。
tonight, the two shall be joined...
祝福もされずに。
...without a single blessing.
「腐り堕ちた眼窩に青い硝子を」
"Blue glass into the decayed eye sockets..."
「破れかけた腕に絹の肌を」
"Silk skin upon the torn arms..."
「侵された内臓に綿のガーゼを」
"Cotton gauze inside the diseased organs..."
「宝石で飾った純白いドレスを」
"A pure white dress adorned with jewels..."
朽ちゆくたび取り繕って、
Repairing her as she continued to decay,
恋を謳って、また医者は
singing of love, once more the doctor
手を染め続けた。
continued to stain his hands.
やがて暴かれたのは
Eventually, what was exposed...
醜い怪物で、
...was an ugly monster.
「それ」を造り上げた医者は、
The doctor who created "it"...
弁駁を叫んだ。
...screamed his defense.
「これは永遠の恋だ。
"This is eternal love!
彼女の願望だ。
It was her desire!
死にゆくと決めたお前らが
You all decided she was to die...
見棄てた女じゃないか」
...isn't she the woman you abandoned?"
鳴呼……哀しき花嫁。
Ah... the tragic bride,
物言えぬままで、
still unable to speak a word.
今宵ふたりは裁かれる。
Tonight, the two will be judged...
彼女を見棄てた人達の正義で。
...by the justice of those who abandoned her.
正しいのはだあれ？
Who is truly in the right?
さて、ハロウィンパーティーもついにフィナーレ！
Now, the Halloween party is finally reaching its finale!
ここで、ご参加くださった国民の皆様へ冥界からのお土産品のご紹介です！
And now, here is a showcase of souvenirs from the underworld for all of our citizens who participated!
お土産品は全４種類。
There are four types of souvenirs in total.
フルセットでご購入いただいた皆様には特典もございます。ご一緒に詳しく見ていきましょう！
For those who purchase the full set, there is also a special bonus. Let's take a closer look together!
まず1つ目、今回の冥界ハロウィンナイトをイメージしたワイドラバーマットです！
First up, the wide rubber mat inspired by this underworld Halloween night!
国王様の横には、冥界の女王の姿が。名を「ナイラ」というそうです。
Next to the king, we see the Queen of the Underworld. Her name is said to be Nyra.
冥界のハロウィンを存分に楽しんでほしいという気持ちを込めた、彼女のイメージソングも、
With the hope that you will fully enjoy the underworld's Halloween, her image song...
この後お披露目予定ですのでお楽しみに！
...is also scheduled to be revealed after this, so please look forward to it!
素敵なイラストは、Matcha様にかいていただきました！
The wonderful illustration was drawn by Matcha-sama!
2つ目は、パスポート風王国シール帳です！
Second is the passport-style kingdom sticker book!
このシール帳には、これからたくさんの思い出を記していきたいですね。
We hope to fill this sticker book with many memories to come.
王国の軌跡として、国民の皆様も今後集めてみてはいかがでしょうか？
As a record of the kingdom's journey, how about starting your collection, everyone?
その一歩として、今回のキービジュアルのステッカーを1枚封入しております！
As a first step, we've included one sticker of this key visual!
3つ目は、SUKONBU FACTORYよりキングフブちゃんぬいぐるみです！
Third, from SUKONBU FACTORY, the King Fubu-chan plushie!
こちらは国王自らデザインをしており、とても愛らしいぬいぐるみとなっております。
This one was designed by the king herself, making it a very adorable plushie.
前回のボリューム1のぬいぐるみをお持ちの方は、ご一緒に飾ってあげてくださいね！
If you have the plushie from Volume 1, please display them together!
4つ目は、王国リボンチャームです！
Fourth is the kingdom ribbon charm!
こちらは秘書である私の胸元のリボンが再現されております。
This is a reproduction of the ribbon worn on my chest as your secretary.
るもよし
...is also fine,
ペンライトにつけるもよしと
or attaching it to a penlight,
多機能なリボンチャームとなっておりますので
as this is a multi-functional ribbon charm.
皆様の「おし活」とやらに、ぜひご活用ください
Please do make use of it for your so-called "Oshikatsu"!
最後は特典のお知らせです
Finally, here is the notice about the purchase bonus.
フルセットご購入の方全員に チェキ風ブロマイドカードを1つお付けいたします
Everyone who purchases the full set will receive a cheki-style bromide card.
複製サインと国王からのメッセージもあるそうですよ
It apparently includes a printed signature and a message from the King.
数量限定バージョンは直筆サイン入りですので 皆様お早めに！
The limited edition version includes a hand-written signature, so hurry up!
以上、今回のお土産品紹介でした！
That's all for this merchandise presentation!
さて
Well then,
この後は冥界の女王様をイメージした楽曲
up next is the song inspired by the Queen of the Underworld,
『冥界Halloween Night!』のお披露目です！
the premiere of "Underworld Halloween Night!"!
楽しまれた後は
After you've enjoyed it,
無事、王国へお帰りくださいね保存
make sure you return safely to the kingdom.
それでは！
With that, let's begin!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come, let's dance
This is Halloween Night!
冥界を挙げての Party (Party)
A party with the entire Underworld (Party)
ルール違反はダメです Warning (Warning)
Violating rules is forbidden, Warning (Warning)
説明は一度きり (きり)
Explanation is only given once (once)
聞き逃せばあの世行き！
Miss it and you're off to the next world!
冗談です♡
Just kidding♡
(いち！) お菓子を回して
(One!) Pass around the candy
(に！) 仮装して盛って！
(Two!) Dress up and look grand!
(さん！) 生者か死者かは隠す事！
(Three!) Hide whether you are living or dead!
(それ！)
(Go!)
(よん！) いつだって笑顔で
(Four!) Always keep a smile
(ご！) 油断禁物です！
(Five!) Do not let your guard down!
最後の最後は無事にご帰宅の事
At the very end, make sure to return home safely
独りきりじゃ つまらないわ
Being all alone is so boring
この退屈な お城の玉座
In this boring castle's throne room
指折りずっと 待ちわびてた
Counting the days, I've been waiting anxiously
人恋しいとか？
Am I lonely?
ヤダ！
No way!
そんなんじゃないってば！
It's not like that at all!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrilling and delightful irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat, showtime of the mad feast!
(Pa Pa Pa) 恐ろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How terrifying
(Pa Pa Pa) 恨めしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How resentful
昔々 憂いさえも忘れてる
Long ago, even grief has been forgotten
あらら？
Oh my?
(Pa Pa Pa) 美味しそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) Delicious looking
(Pa Pa Pa) 魂だわ！
(Pa Pa Pa) souls!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come, let's dance
This is Halloween Night!
響く楽団の Tuning (Tuning)
The orchestra's tuning echoes (Tuning)
その不協和音さえも Music (Music)
Even that dissonance is Music (Music)
王室のドアが開き (開き)
The royal doors open wide (open)
拍手喝采が起こる
Thunderous applause breaks out
快感です♡
It feels so good♡
(いち！) ロウソクを灯して
(One!) Light up the candles
(に！) ドレス纏って！
(Two!) Wear your dress!
(さん！) 女王の私の お出ましです！
(Three!) The appearance of me, the Queen!
(さあさあ！)
(Come, come!)
(よん！) 手を取り合って
(Four!) Take each other's hands
(ご！) 今日は無礼講で！
(Five!) Tonight there are no formalities!
私に魅せられちゃったら 最期です
If you are captivated by me, it is the end
鮮やかなステップ くるり舞ってワルツ
With brilliant steps, twirling to a Waltz
百鬼夜行のリズムに揺られて保存
Swayed by the rhythm of the Night Parade
この楽しさ 癖になるわ
This fun is becoming addictive
時間切れとか？
Is time running out?
ヤダ！
No way!
全然足りないってば！
It's not nearly enough!
Let's 冥界 Halloween Night!
Let's Underworld Halloween Night!
Dancing! Dancing! 一夜の奇っ怪なメモリー
Dancing! Dancing! A bizarre memory of one night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat Underworld Halloween Night!
Sweety! Sweety! おもむろに頬張るキャンディー
Sweety! Sweety! Slowly stuffing candy in my cheeks
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ ああ、もっと頂戴！
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat, oh, give me more!
うたかたの夢 淡い霧の中溶けて
A fleeting dream, melting into the pale mist
蒼白い頬を 涙が伝った
Tears streamed down the pale cheeks
この歌は誰の為？ 自問自答の末
For whom is this song? After questioning myself
禁断の箱を開けたら
Once I open the forbidden box,
時間を戻す 魔法使っちゃおっかな！
maybe I should use magic to turn back time!
Dancing! Dancing! 闇夜にハッピーなメロディー
Dancing! Dancing! A happy melody in the dark night
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 冥界 Halloween Night!
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat Underworld Halloween Night!
Swinging! Swinging! ゾッとして愉快なアイロニー
Swinging! Swinging! A thrilling and delightful irony
ラッタッタ ラッタッタ 狂宴のショータイム！
Rat-tat-tat Rat-tat-tat, showtime of the mad feast!
(Pa Pa Pa) おそろしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How terrifying
(Pa Pa Pa) うらめしや
(Pa Pa Pa) How resentful
昔々 憂いさえも忘れてる
Long ago, even grief has been forgotten
あらら？
Oh my?
(Pa Pa Pa) おいしそうな
(Pa Pa Pa) Delicious looking
(Pa Pa Pa) たましいだわ！
(Pa Pa Pa) souls!
Welcome! さあ、踊ろうよ
Welcome! Come, let's dance
This is Halloween Night!
ハロウィンパーティー、いかがでしたでしょうか？
How did you enjoy the Halloween party?
ちゃんとこちら側の王国に戻ってこられていますか？
Have you managed to return safely to our kingdom?
冥界の女王様に気に入られてしまうと、魂を奪われてしまって、帰ってこられませんからね。
If the Queen of the Underworld takes a liking to you, she'll steal your soul and you won't be able to return.
戻ってこられて、ラッキーでした！なんて、ふふっ。
You were lucky to make it back! Just kidding, hehe.
あ、今日のお話はどうでしたか？楽しかったでしょうか？
Oh, how did you like today's stories? Were they fun?
私が特にお気に入りは、探偵のお話でして...
My personal favorite was the detective story...
今回お聞かせできて、とても嬉しかったです。
I was so happy to be able to share it with you this time.
そうだ、いつかあなたのお話も聞かせてくださいね。
Oh, right! Please tell me your story someday, too.
もしかすると、あの本に、あなたのお話も書き記されるかもしれませんよ。
Who knows, your story might even be written down in that book.
何と言っても、摩訶不思議な本ですから。
After all, it is a very mysterious book.
何が起こるか、司書である私にもわかりません。
Even as the librarian, I have no idea what might happen next.
さて、そろそろお時間ですね。
Well, it is almost time.
またお話が聞きたくなりましたら、
If you ever wish to hear another story,
いつでもこの、王国図書館へお越しください。
you are welcome to visit this Kingdom Library anytime.
それでは、さようなら。
And so, farewell.
ハジマリはきっと ひとつの願い それを抱いて私たちは 生まれた
The beginning is surely a single wish, and embracing it, we were born...
孤独な夜空 震える指先で 天と天を繋げよう
In the lonely night sky, with trembling fingertips, let's connect the heavens together!
すこん部の皆さん 準備はできてますか？
Everyone in Sukonbu, are you ready?
セイ・ホー・レッツ・ゴー いきますよ！
Say ho, let's go! Here we go!
セイ！ ほら 俯いた顔を上げて みんなで手を取れば、ほら！
Say! Look up from your downcast face, if everyone takes each other's hands, look!
はい！ まだまだ道は途中
Yes! We're still on our way,
世界を越えよう
let's go beyond the world!
セイ！ ほら 押し押しが我儘
Say! Look, my support is selfish,
止まらない 全力ですから
and unstoppable because I'm giving it my all!
夢を描き終えたら
Once we've finished drawing our dreams,
追いかけ続けよう
let's keep chasing after them!
共に 鳴る ファンファーレ ゴー！
Let the fanfare ring out together, go!
だから気が付いた 自分自身の 輝きを見失ったときには
So when you realize you've lost sight of your own shine,
思い出してね 僕らの星座は 君がいるから輝く
please remember that our constellation shines because you are here.
無数の星の中
Among countless stars,
光を君がくれた
you gave me light.
もっと 越えて行けるさ
We can go even further!
スーパーノヴァを起こせ今
Cause a supernova right now!
何度だって飛べる
We can fly as many times as it takes!
これは 紛れもなく 僕らの軌跡
This is, without a doubt, our miracle!
ハイファイン！
Hi-Fine!
ラストメッセージ！すこん部ーー！
Last message! Sukonbu!